# Arghajit Bhattacharya

Software Engineer with 6 years of industry experience in software development Life cycle. Proficient building Test Automation framework and solutions for different project stack from scratch. Worked with front end, back end, automation pipelines side by side. Holds production level exposure of end to end product development and workflow. Worked with Python, Java and Node stacks. Guided team of Engineers on different occasions.

#### SKILLS

Python TypeScript NPM AWS ECS, Lambda,

JavaHTML/PUG/EJS/HBRPostgresFirebaseJavaScriptCSS/SCSS/SASSMySQLGit

Node/ExpressJS Bootstrap Firebase Selenium
Angular2 Gulp testNG/JUnit

#### EXPERIENCES

## Software Engineer in Test II - Python Backend Chegg (New, Delhi, India)

Dec 2018 - Present

www.arghajit.work

Work with a global team to develop, test and maintain company's microservices product suite. Responsible to build Test Automation frameworks and support till operational. Created framework from scratch using Python, Robot Framework, , Jenkins, Docker, Selenium, BrowserStack. Maintain and stands responsible for Automated scheduled build jobs at Jenkins. Works with vendor AWS stack. Technical guidance to resources at different geographical locations.

### Senior Test Automation Engineer (Lead)

May 2018 - Dec 2018

#### EPAM Systems (Hyderabad, India)

Worked with different functional teams to deliver a B2B portal of a world leading financial institute. Worked with a team of SDETs to deliver Features and Enhancements of the product. Worked in Sprints under SAFe. Regular communication with Onsite Project Managers and client side Analysts.

#### Senior Test Engineer

Sep 2016 - May 2018

#### Belzabar Software Design (New Delhi, India)

Work with a global team to develop, test and maintain company's microservices product suite. Responsible to build Test Automation frameworks and support till operational. Created framework from scratch using Python, Robot Framework, , Jenkins, Docker, Selenium, BrowserStack. Maintain and stands responsible for Automated scheduled build jobs at Jenkins. Works with vendor AWS stack. Technical guidance to resources at different geographical locations.

#### Software QA Engineer

Sep 2016 - May 2018

Belzabar Software Design (New Delhi, India)

Work with a global team to develop, test and maintain company's microservices product suite. Responsible to build Test Automation frameworks and support till operational. Created framework from scratch using Python,

#### QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Technology

Jul 2008 - Aug 2012

West Bengal University of Technology (Kolkata, India)